《实习医生格蕾》前情回顾
Previously on Grey's Anatomy
你有问题  你的问题大了
You've got some problems. You've got some big problems.
我和一个儿科医生接吻了
I kissed a peds surgeon.
可莱奥普  这位是朱丽  我的女朋友
Calliope this is Julie my date.
我跟莱西好上了
I'm seeing lexie.
我的天  那个被我弄断了
Oh my god! i think i broke it.
这位是病人甲
This is patient "x."
女性  29岁  被我院误诊为贫血
She's a 29-year-old female we misdiagnosed with anemia.
我在申请儿科研究奖学金
I'm applying for a fellowship in pediatric surgery.
你违背了我们先前的决定
which is not what we have discussed!
我老婆在哪  是你杀了她  你是凶手
Where's my wife? You killed her. you're a murderer.
每位医生都有一片阴影
Every surgeon I know has a shadow...
其中充满恐惧与怀疑
A dark cloud of fear and doubt
哪怕是最好的医生也不例外
That follows even the best of us into the O.R.
-这家伙醉了  -他没醉
- Dude he is fried. - He's not fried.
他医死了个病人  还遭到起诉
He lost a patient and got hit with a lawsuit all in one week.
他需要时间
He just needs time.
他都坐在那三天了
He's been sitting there for three days.
屁股都快跟沙发垫子长一起了
The sofa cushions are gonna start bonding to his ass
-他把我的麦片都吃完了  -他在消化
- And he's eating all my cereal. - he's taking stock.
生活发生了如此重大的转折
Something huge and life-altering happened to him
他正在消化
And he's taking stock
思考下一步怎么走
Figuring out his next move.
我们别责怪他  也别催他
We shouldn't judge him. we shouldn't rush him.
随便吧  就当是希尔维亚 普莱斯在挑棉花糖
Whatever. Sylvia Plath's picking out all the marshmallows.
尽情享受吧
They're the best part.
我确信他坐在我的钥匙上
and i'm pretty sure that he's sitting on my keys.
我想让他挪一下  但他看上去这么  舒服
I'd ask him to move but he looks so... comfy.
一群胆小鬼
Oh you guys are cowards.
你在吃东西呢  有胃口是好事
You're eating. that's good. appetite is good.
还有什么好事呢  洗个痛快澡
You know what else is good? showering cleansing water.
你可以洗个痛快澡  然后去医院
Are you thinking you'll shower maybe go into the hospital?
我得去提交证词
I have to for the deposition.
我得去向那男人详细解释
I have to go and explain in detail
我是怎么杀了她怀孕的老婆
How i killed a man's pregnant wife.
很好啊  我不是指杀人
That's good. i mean not the killing part
但我觉得你会感觉舒服些  如果你能
But the--i-i think you'll feel better once you...
去  上班
Go to... work.
他不会有事的
He'll be fine.
人们假装阴影不在身边
We pretend the shadow isn't there...
满心期望  如果能拯救更多生命
Hoping that if we save more lives
掌握更高的技术
Master harder techniques
跑得更快更远
Run faster and farther
它就会放弃追逐我们
It'll get tired and give up the chase.
但常言道
But like they say...
影不离人
You can't outrun your shadow.
早上好
Morning.
有一次我做梦
I dreamt once
梦到自己掉下窗外  抓着一把帘子悬空着
I was falling out a window hanging on to the drapes.
醒来发现自己抓着梅丽狄斯的头发
I woke up pulling Meredith's hair out.
刚送来一位伤员
So we have a trauma coming in.
在橄榄球场里被踩了
A trampling on a football field--
我不用你帮
no i-i don't need your help.
可我今天跟着你干
Oh but i'm on your service today.
我告诉你  杨医生
and i'm telling you, Dr. Yang,
-照顾好自己的手肘  -你在这呢
- I want you to take care of that elbow. - there you are.
-你怎么了  -滑了一跤  我没事
- What happened to you? - i tripped and fell. it's fine.
不  你有事
No. no it's not.
没什么大不了的
It's... it's nothing.
只是一场意外  你又怎么了
It's--it was an accident. what's wrong with you?
德瑞克不肯从沙发上爬起来
Uh derek won't get off the couch.
真像个娘们儿
So the weaker sex.
还肿着  再休息一天
It's still swollen. i'd give it another day of rest.
我都三天没手术了
I haven't operated in three days.
别握着手术刀害人了
Don't hit people with your scalpel in hand.
-你找他谈过没  -他先动手的
- Have you talked to him yet? - he threw the first punch.
是你找的时机不对
Well you did catch him at a bad time.
他是医死了个病人
so he lost a patient
但我们是医生  手术失败很正常
We're surgeons. we're men. we lose patients.
这不代表他有权利
It doesn't give him the right
表现得像个醉鬼
To go around behaving like a drunk frat boy.
你要我低声下气地求他原谅
And now i'm supposed to go crawling back begging for his forgiveness?
-怎么了  你干什么  -嘘
- What uh-- what are you doing? - shh. shh. shh shh shh.
我对那位儿科医生吐露了真言
I went all "say anything" on the peds surgeon
结果她女朋友在场
In front of the peds surgeon's date
-所以我在躲她  -你"成熟"
- So now i am hiding from the peds surgeon. - mature.
你参与斗殴  无权评论我
Um you got in a fistfight. no judging.
手
Hand!
手  天哪  抱歉  我忘了
Hand! oh god. i'm sorry. i... i forgot.
真抱歉  这一切都是我的错
I--i'm so sorry. i feel terrible about everything
你们打架  你的手  德瑞克
About the fight and your hand and derek and...
他现在情绪很糟
You know he's not doing so well
我觉得你该找他谈谈
I really think that you should talk to him.
我找他谈
I should talk to him?
瞧瞧你  挂着听诊器填表格
Look at you--your stethoscope around your neck charting...
我可以预见  你十年后
I can totally see you in ten years
会成为一个又帅又牛的主治医生
A little salt and pepper in your hair big-shot attending.
阿历克斯  你会名扬天下的
You're gonna be a rock star alex.
-有何居心  -怎么了
- What is this? - what
我就不能幻想下自己男朋友的
I can't fantasize about my boyfriend
璀璨未来吗
And his bright bright future?
闭嘴
Shut up.
斯蒂文斯医生  我们研究了病人甲的案例
Dr. stevens we've been working on the patient "x" case
-想出了一些主意  -很好  我们走
- And we have a couple of ideas. - great let's get to work.
什么是"病人甲"
What's this patient "x" thing
把实习生都占了
That's taking all the interns?
什么时候能结束
And when's it gonna be over?
-我需要奴才给我打下手  -新的教学计划
- I need minions to do my crap work. - Some new teaching thing.
我们都巴不得能进手术室
you know we're all killing ourselve to get into the O.R.
伊兹上次拿手术刀是什么时候
When's the last time izzie held a scalpel?
她要掉队了  就要成为欧麦利第二
She's falling behind. she's like the new o'malley.
伊兹不会成为欧麦利第二
Izzie's nothing like o'malley. hello.
欧麦利去门诊
Okay o'malley you're in the clinic.
格蕾和杨跟着我
Grey and yang you're with me.
-克莱夫去急诊跟着亨特  -贝利医生
- Karev you're in the pit with hunt. - oh no dr. bailey
应该是我去外伤科的
I'm supposed to be on trauma today.
别争了  杨  亨特点名要克莱夫
save it yang. hunt wants Karev.
主任你来了
sir there you are. uh--
谢博德今天会赏脸过来吗
Shepherd planning to grace us with his presence today?
会的  他没事了
Yes, he's fine.
主任  我一早上都在呼你
Sir i--i've been trying to page you all morning.
你有时间的话  我需要你帮忙
I could use your help on a case if you're available.
-今天不去儿科了  -不去
- No peds today? - um no.
又是做善事
Must be slumming.
您说什么
Excuse me? s--
雀沙 舍利  31岁  梅根 舍利  27岁
Tricia Shelley 31 Megan Shelley 27
迈克尔 舍利  23岁
Michael shelley 23
基因测试表明他们都携带
Genetic testing revealed they all carry
会引起遗传性弥漫型胃癌的CDH1基因
The cdh1 gene for hereditary diffuse gastric cancer.
解释一下  格蕾医生
Which means what dr. grey?
就是说  他们都有四分之三的可能
which means they all have a 3-in-4 chance
会患上胃癌
of developing the cancer.
贝利医生把我们上一辈每一位的肿瘤
Dr. bailey has taken tumors out of pretty much everyone
都取出来了
On our mother's side.
很不幸  这种癌症很厉害
unfortunately it's a highly aggressive cancer.
肿瘤生长非常快  等我拿出来时
The tumors grow quickly so by the time i get in there--
已经遗传到了下一代
Our family tree is down to a branch.
布德叔叔情况怎样
How is uncle Bud doing?
死了
Dead.
-海伦阿姨呢  -死了
- And aunt Helen?  - dead.
-明尼苏达的那个远亲呢  -活着
- What about the Minnesota cousin? - not dead.
她体重有90磅  关在疗养院里了
She's 90 pounds and in hospice meg.
可还没死
Still not dead yet.
那么  你们
So uh you've...
决定要接受进一步治疗
Decided you're ready to take the next step.
我们定了协议  同进同退
We've made a pact. we're all in this together.
请把我们的胃切了  贝利医生
Cut our stomachs out dr. bailey.
贝斯 迪亚本  17岁  有癫痫史
Beth Dearborn 17 year old with a history of seizures--
行进乐队表演时癫痫大发作
Had a grand mal during a marching band performance.
抵院后再次发作
Started seizing again upon arrival.
-静推2单位劳拉西泮  -病人室颤
- Push 2 of lorazepam. - she's in v-fib.
换氧  极板充电200焦
Ventilate and charge the paddles to 200.
等等  室颤可能是癫痫造成的假象
Wait. the v-fib could be just artifact from the seizure.
如果采用电击  而她却没有室颤
If we shock her and she's no actually in v-fib
-心脏会停止  有脉搏吗  -好象有
- She'll flatline. you got a pulse? - i-i think so.
我不确定  很难区别
i don't know. It's hard to tell
-劳拉西泮不起作用  -怎么办
- Lorazepam's not working. damn it. - what do we do?
用电击的话  是死是活全凭天意
We shock her and save her or shock her and kill her.
拼了
What the hell...
让开
Clear.
Clear!
窦性心动过速
Sinus tach.
判断得好  亨特医生
Good call dr. hunt.
一半对一半的概率
Ah it was a 50-50 shot.
不会吧  又来了
Oh no. it happened again?
贝斯  我是值班的儿科医生罗宾斯
Beth i'm Dr. Robbins the pediatric surgeon on call.
这位是亨特医生
This is dr. hunt.
你行进表演时被踩踏得很严重
You got beat up pretty bad while you were marching.
我们要给你检查是否受了内伤
We're gonna run some tests check for internal injuries.
我在表演时发作的吗
I seized during the performance?
-我吃了药了  -别紧张
- But i took my meds. - relax.
又不是尿裤子了
it's not like you crapped your pants or anything.
跟尿裤子有什么区别
It's like i crapped my pants.
我在全行进乐队面前癫痫发作
I had a seizure in front of the entire marching band
比尿裤子还难堪
It is exactly like i crapped my pants.
他们会杀了我的
They're gonna kill me.
-谁  -癫痫特护
- Who? - seizure patrol.
你们就是癫痫特护
You are the seizure patrol?
我是菲利沙 克莱内特  他是若麦加
I Felicia Clairnet. He's Romajor.
每次贝斯一发作  我们就得丢掉乐器
Whenever Beth has a seizure, we have to drop our instruments
冲到她身旁按住她  防止她咬掉舌头
and go roll her on her sides or she's choked on her tongue
我们当时正在西北区行进
We were in the middle of northwest regional parade,
形势大好
we were favorite to win.
直到贝斯掉了小军鼓以及木管乐器
Yeah, until Beth dropped down the snare drum，half the Woodwinds
我俩想阻止  但她就在队列中心
the two were trying to avoid, but she was right in the middle of formation
知道了  你们去通知她的家长吧
Yeah, ok. Why don't you just go call her parents.
把测试做了  她已经心脏停跳一次了
You run some test, she's already coded once.
你给我看着她  扶着急救车守着
I want you to watch her and stand by with the crash cart
你要我照顾这个害乐队输比赛的家伙
You want me to sit here and babysit the band nerd?
-这是实习生干的活儿  -我找不到实习生
- That's an intern job  - I don't see any interns around.
格蕾医生
Dr. Grey.
病人甲  29岁女性  之前身体健康
Patient "x", a previously healthy 29-year old female
生命体征稳定  体检正常
presenting a stable vital signs and normal physical exam
症状表现为偶然右上象限腹痛  恶心
and with symptoms of occasional right-upper quadrant pain, nausea
伴有幻觉
and hallucinations.
头部断层扫描  胸片  CBC指标都正常
Head CT, chest X-rays, c.b.c. were normal
化验显示乳酸脱氢酶含量升高
But chemistries revealed an elevated l.d.h.
现在你们是她的医生
So you are this girl's doctor.
她求助于你
She comes to you
她很担心  不知道问题出在哪
She's scared she doesn't know what's wrong.
你们来诊断她  下一步怎么做
You have to diagnose her. what do you do next?
-你们打算做什么检查  -RC监测或者要么PS检查行不行?
- What test do you run? - how about a retic count or perfell smail?
你是在浪费时间
You'd be wasting your time.
CBC正常  记得吗
The c.b.c. was normal remember?
既然你说是腹痛
You said there was abdominal pain.
上胃肠道检查如何
What about an upper g.i.?
很好  病人甲的医生做了此检查
Good. that is exactly what patient x's doctor did next.
看出什么来了
What does this tell us?
这些是什么
What is all this?
预防性胃切除术可能造成的副作用
Possible side effects and complications
及并发症
from prophylactic gastrectomy
让你们了解术后的反应
So post-op you know what to expect.
营养不良  虚弱无力
Malnourishment weakness fatigue...
-胃倾倒症  -听上去很恐怖
- Dumping syndrome? - oh that doesn't sound good.
可能会肛漏
Possible anal leakage?
胃切除术不是阑尾炎手术
A gastrectomy isn't like getting your appendix out.
这将改变整个消化系统
We're changing the way your entire digestive system works.
-对人体改变巨大  -我是兄弟会的老大
- This is a serious adjustment. - i'm the president of my frat.
我有女朋友  还要去滑雪
I have a girlfriend. i go snowboarding.
我要是变成了虚弱无力
How am i supposed to do all that stuff
又肛漏的老头子  我还怎么生活啊
When i'm suddenly this weak old man with anal leakage?
你知道这对雀沙很重要
You know how important this is to Trish.
我们从小就听雀沙摆布
Trish has run our lives since we are little kids.
她决定去哪吃饭
She decides where we go to dinner
去哪度假  去哪过感恩节
Where we go on vacation where we do thanksgiving.
我都23岁了  我不想把自己剁了
I'm 23 years old. if i don't want to butcher myself
-她没法逼我  -你是宁愿死
- She can't make me. - so you'd rather die
像母亲一样  还是像爷爷  像布德叔叔那样
like mom or grandpa? Or uncle Bud?
这可不是短痛  痛苦将慢慢延续
And it's not quick Mike. it's a slow painful way to go.
有四分之一的几率不会得癌  不是吗
There's a 1-in-4 shot we don't get it right?
-值得一搏  -别犯傻了
- That's something!  - don't be stupid.
你必须做  我们说好的
You are doing this and we discussed it.
你再也别想管我了
You're not in charge of me anymore!
梅格
Meg?
我没想到会这么严重
I didn't realize it was such a big deal.
我只是
I just...
我需要一点时间想清楚
I just need a little time to think about it okay?
错了  考乐翰做搭桥
No no no. Callahan on the bypass.
卫英做阑尾手术
Vin on the appy.
该死的开颅术  谢博德死哪去了
Damn craniotomy... where the hell is shepherd?!
你不能靠谢博德  主任
Uh you can't rely on shepherd sir.
我能帮你什么吗
Is there anything i can do for you?
我的神经外科医生失踪多天了
Well my neurosurgeon's been missing for days
心脏科主任还空缺着
I still have no head of cardio
普外科医生时不时离我而去
I've got general surgeons quitting on me left and right
手术都堆成山了
I've got surgeries piling up like dead fish
却没有医生来做
And no surgeons to do 'em.
现在不是好时机  但我得说
well then now, would probably be a bad time to tell you
我的手还没恢复  没法手术
That my hand's still out of commission. And i can't operate.
给我安排手术  主任
You know what? leave me on the board chief.
-我不会让你失望  -我可以做开颅  主任
- I won't let you down. - i could do that craniotomy chief.
安排尼尔森医生做开颅术
Put Dr. Nelson on the craniotomy.
谢谢你  约翰
Appreciate it john.
我叫吉姆
It's--it's jim.
你是新来的吧  欢迎来到西雅图圣恩
You must be new. welcome to seattle grace.
我在这儿干了十年了
I've been here ten years.
在谢博德从纽约杀过来前
I was the interim chief of neuro
我是这儿的神经外科主任
Before sheerd and his red cape swooped in from new york.
我是马克·斯隆  整形外科的
Mark sloan plastics.
我们见过...三次了
We've met... three times.
我不知道碧姆先生为什么会让她加入乐队
I don't know why mr. bimm ever let her even join band.
-她吹横笛一点都不专业  -够了  出去
Not like she's a master flautist. okay get out.
碧姆先生要我们在这儿陪她  直到...
Mr. bimm says we're supposed to stay with her till her--
我知道  我现在也给她做检查
I got it. i'm seizure patrol now.
你那些朋友真混蛋
Your friends are asses.
他们不是我的朋友
They're not my friends.
一旦让全校的人都看到你出丑
Once you spaz out in front of the whole scho
你就别想着再有朋友了
Friends are kinda hard to come by.
我知道你控制不了抽搐
i know you can't help the AAAA
但没人逼你加入军鼓队啊
But nobody made you join the marching band.
那里面是一堆神经病
That's like spreading nerd on nerd.
我喜欢待在乐队里  知道吗
i like being in the band, ok?
这貌似是我唯一擅长的东西了
It's like the one thing i'm actually good at.
-你在高中里玩什么的  -摔跤
-What'd you do in high school?  -I wrestled.
你玩摔跤?  你的身材看不出嘛
You're a wrestler? you wearing tights under that lab coat?
那是很久以前的事了
It was long time ago.
我那时是高中生  现在是外科医生
That was in high school. i'm a surgeon now.
那如果每次要进手术室的时候
Fine. then how would you feel if you seized
都发生抽搐你会作何感受
Every time you went into the operating room?
我明白了
Yeah okay.
你知道我作为你的医生
You realize that as your doctor
你不会建议你这样做的  对吧
I'm not recommending this, right?
我需要完成今天的手术
I need to get through my surgeries today.
今年你是有的受了
Oh you're gonna get through them
今天伤患一片
You're just gonna be in a world of hurt later.
你听说过神经外科的尼尔森医生吗
You heard of a dr. nelson in neuro?
噢  对
Oh yeah.
阴暗版的谢博德
Shadow shepherd.
-阴暗版谢博德?  -是啊
Shadow shepherd? yeah.
他是个不错的医生
He's a solid surgeon
不过算是谢博德的残废版本吧
But sort of the j.v. player to shepherd's varsity
-山寨版谢博德 是谢博德的垫脚石头  -我懂了
-the B team to shepherd. The brick layer to shepherd's architect.  -I get it.
就因为那人没发表过惊人的研究报告
Just 'cause the guy doesn't publish fancy clinical trials
或是做过旷世的手术  又没有特别拽的发型
Or take on flashy surgery or have creepy perfect hair
他就不算是个人了
He's less of a man?
大概吧
Kinda.
和律师谈得怎样
How'd it go with the lawyers?
他们统计了我手下的死亡率
They told me my death rate.
这些是我救活的人
These are the people i saved.
这些是我没救活的
These are the people i killed.
但是
Ok, well most
大多数来找你的病人已经病危了
People were terminal when they came to you.
你是他们最后的希望
You were their last chance.
你在绝望中寻找希望
And you take on impossible cases.
想想那么多的临床实验吧
Look at the clinical trial.
我杀了那么多人
So many people...
比大漠和曼森还有本迪杀的加起来都多
(三人都是杀了超过二十人的连环杀手)
More than dahmer manson bundy combined.
你得从大局来看
You're not looking at the big picture.
这就是整个大局
This is the big picture.
噢  谢博德  你总算回来了
Oh shepherd. thank god you're back.
今天你能做两个大脑活体组织检查吗
Can you swing two brain biopsies today?
我不做手术  理查德
I'm not operating richard.
听着  我知道你现在
Look, I know you've got
有个要命的大官司要打
A big lawsuit breathing down your neck
我知道你治死了一个病人
And i know you lost a patient
但我要你回来做
But i need you back to work doing the job
我聘你做的事
i hired you to do.
-我不做手术  -我不是请求你  而是作为主任
I am not operating. I am not asking i'm telling
命令你
As chief surgeon of this hospital
今天你不回来工作试试看  谢博德
If you don get back to that O.R. today shepherd...
他就这样走出去了
And he just walked out.
什么都没说就走了
Without saying a word he just walked out.
亨特从早上对我现代启示录一番后
hunt won't even look at me.
连看都不愿看我一眼
Since all "apocalypse now" on me this morning.
我还得开开心心地去给病人开脑
I had to get all scalpel happy up that patient's brain.
他现在看都不看一眼
And now he can't face it.
他把我当什么了  没用的花?
He thinks i'm what? like the worthless flower?
-我才是强者  -拜托  我才是强者
Well guess what. i'm the strong one. my god he just walked out.
如果我得了胃癌  我绝对会做胃切除术
If i have the stomach cancer gene, I would get gastrectomy to be no problem.
-我会面对  我不逃避  -德瑞克选择逃避
I face things. i don't walk away. derek walks away.
也许逃避才是正解
maybe walking is the answer.
看吧  这不是情绪化  而是科学
See it's not emotional. it's science.
你有问题  就去面对
You have a problem don't ignore it.
但有时候压力太大了只能逃避
well sometimes if you have to pain ignored does go away.
你俩真有趣
You guys are hilarious.
你到底知不知道她在说什么
I mean do you even know what she just said?
而她又在说什么
Or what she just said?
我可以预见你俩五十年后在养老院里
I can totally see you guys in 50 years in a nursing home
互不相干地一起诉苦
Just talking at each other with your hearing aids off.
真  有趣
Hi-larious!
噢  我爱午餐
Oh i love lunch.
糟糕了
What the hell?
贝斯  蓝色警报!
Beth? code blue!
在我取出胃以后  该做什么  杨?
After i take out the stomach s i'll do what yang?
做食管接合
Sew the esophageal anastomosis.
或者  另一种方案是什么  格蕾?
Or the other option is grey?
也可以做钉合术
You could staple the anastomosis.
为什么要这么做
Now why would i want to do that?
这样可以降低胰瘘发生率
fistula rates can be higher when you hand some.
你也许会说用老办法
You might say that using the old stapler
是我的专长
Is sort of my specialty.
我觉得你的专长是照顾孩子
I thought your specialty was babysitting children.
我肯定现在你情愿干那个
Uh... i'm sure you'd rather be doing that right now.
老实说  主任  我的确这么想
Frankly sir i feel like i am.
抱歉  主任  这里有问题
Excuse me sir. i think you should feel this.
就在这儿
Right here.
希望不是我想象的那样
Tell me that's not what i think it is.
噢  等等  我想我知道了
Whoa whoa. wait wait. i think i got it.
肝脏酶指标正常  心脏检查呈阴性
Liver enzymes are normal cardiac workup is negative--
如果乳酸脱氢酶是假阳性的话...
If l.d.h. is a false positive--
-这是个骗人的把戏  -什么
It's a trick question. what?
她很健康  x病人没有病
She's fine. patient "x" is fine.
她有病
She's not fine.
她的血沉速率微高
Okay well her sed rate is slightly elevated.
我们给她检查过免疫性疾病吗
Did we check for autoimmune disease?
检查了抗核抗体和血清都正常
yeah a.n.a. and c.r.p were negative too.
她最坏也就是个焦虑症
At worst she's got an anxiety disorder.
这女孩完全健康  她..
The girl is totally fine. she is...
她病了!
She is not fine!
她有幻觉
She had hallucinations.
她的视  听  触都产生了幻觉
She had visual auditory and tactile hallucinations
她能看到死去的未婚夫
About her dead fianc?
她感觉自己在跟他聊天
She thought she could talk to him
能碰到他
And touch him.
她病了
She's not fine.
你们漏查了什么东西
You're missing something.
你们查错地方了
You're not looking in the right place.
回去看看漏查了什么
Go back and figure out what you're missing.
真的吗  雀沙患了癌症?
She has it? Chesa has cancer?
她的癌症处于第一期
Well the cancer was stage one
幸好发现得早
Since we got to it so early
胃切除术可以治愈她
The gastrectomy was probably curative.
她几个月前才做了胃窥镜检查
She just had her endoscopy a few months ago.
这种癌症来势很突然  而且蔓延很开
It was an aggressive cancer that grew quickly.
-事实上我们今天取出了她的胃  -从而救了她一命
-The fact we took her stomach today.  -It saved your sister's life.
雀沙决定好所有事是因为...
The reason Trish decides everything--
感恩节  晚餐  假期...
Thanksgiving dinners vacations--
她是我们中唯一一个
She's the only one left who knows how to cook
会做烤鸡的人
A turkey mike.
她是唯一一个喜欢计划假期怎么过的人
She's the only one left who likes planning vacations.
她是唯一一个会记得
And she's the only one left who ever remembers
去餐厅定位子的人
To make dinner reservations.
她来管我们是因为其他能管事的人都死了
She's in charge of us because everyone else is dead.
我想就现在吧
I want it now.
现在就动手术
I want the surgery right now.
为什么要按警报  她只是抽搐而已
Why is she coding when she seizes?
没道理的啊
It doesn't make any sense.
这么年轻的女孩  心脏不会有事
Not in a girl this young. her heart should be fine.
贝斯发作前按的警报  不是发作的当中
Beth coded before her seizure not during it.
我看到她的心脏产生室颤
I saw her heart go into v-fib.
她才17岁  没有心脏病史  克莱夫
she's 17 with no heart history, karev.
我知道  但我在监视器上看到了
Yeah i know but i saw it on the monitor.
你以为你看到了
you think you saw on the monitor.
她发作的时候混乱一片  作为医生紧张了也情有可原
Seizures are chaotic. doctors panic in the moment.
我没有紧张
I didn't panic.
你是不是要我去跟她父母说
Are you suggesting that i tell that girl and her parents
她整整六年被误诊为癫痫?
That she's been wrongly treated for epilepsy for six years?
我觉得我们应该为她动手术
and then i think we should call
你要我知法犯法地
With an e.p. study. you want me to deliberately shock
毁了一个孩子健康的心脏?
A perfectly healthy child's heart?
我绝不这么做
Ablutely not.
亨特医生
Dr. hunt.
如果他是正确的  那警报就合理了
If he's right it would explain the coding.
-如果他错了  就误伤了一条人命  -听着  我没错!
-If he's wrong it will kill her  -Look I'm not wrong!
由你负责了  克莱夫
Then it's your call karev.
也许克里斯蒂娜是对的
Maybe cristina's right.
也许去教导实习医生是没有意义的
Maybe trying to teach the interns is pointless.
拜托  别听克里斯蒂娜的
Please. don't listen to cristina.
她这么说是因为你情愿教他们
She thinks just because you'd rather teach
也不愿意承认你在重蹈我的覆辙
Than take out a gall bladder that you're the new me.
欧麦利的下场
O'malley the sequel.
欧麦利2.0版本
O'malley 2.0.
你看的报告比我多  做的研究比我多
You read more journals and do more research
也花了更多的时间在实验室里训练
And log more hours in the skills lab
比这里任何的住院医生都多
Than any other resident here.
你从没有放弃做一个更好的医生
You never give up on trying to be a better doctor
你也不是踩着别人往上爬的人
And you don't step on other people to do it.
能走你的老路  我很幸运
I would be lucky to be the new you.
你是要告诉我X病人的事吗
Are you gonna tell me about patient "x"?
我知道我们漏掉了什么  走吧  乔治
I know what we missed. gotta go George.
她淋巴结肿大了  对吗
Okay she had enlarged lymph nodes right?
不过不只一个
But it's not mono.
要我们漏掉了她脑里一个肿瘤怎么办
So what if we missed a malignancy in her brain?
通过CT扫描已经排除了
Well you already ruled that out with
我想CT扫描出了错
A c.t. i think that a mistake.
我想做个带显影剂的核磁共振
I'd like to order an m.r.i. with contrast
也许可以切除一块肿瘤
Maybe biopsy a lymph node.
不管X病人有什么问题
Whatever's wrong with patient "x "
-也已经在她脑子里了对吗 -是的
- It's already in her brain isn't it? - yeah.
手术钳进入
Clamp's going in.
-没有感觉到肿块  - 那就2-0缝线吧
- I don't feel any masses. - 2-0 vicryl please.
如果是我会再做一次
Uh sir if i may one more time
我想还是不错的选择
I think stilling would be a better choice.
贝利医生  如果我不犯错的话
If i'm not mistaken dr Bally
希望能是这医院里一个常规手术
Wish to be a general surgeon in this hospital.
那为什么我不让机器做呢
So why don't we leave the technical calls up to me？
我只是简单陈述意见
I was simply express my opinion
在什么最有利于我的病人这件事上
On what would be best for my patient.
那好你没有把意见说清楚
Okay you don't get a opinion clear.
这是我的医院所以是我的病人
This is my patient because this is my hospital.
在你的医院你可以做该死的决定
When it's your hospital you can make the damn decisions.
不过到现在为止是我的医院
But until then this is my hospital!
你们所有的人都要照我说的做
And I want all of you people to do what i say!
好的
Yes sir.
2-0缝合吧
2-0 vicryl please.
你会好起来的
You're gonna be okay.
你被照顾的很好
You're in really good hands.
我想再问你一次  克来夫
I'm gonna ask you one more time Karev...
这事你确定吗
Are you sure about this?
没错
Yeah.
那你来做救火队吧
Then you're on crash cart.
如果你干的话
If you're ong...
准备好这个
Be ready use it.
你的路径报告复原的很清楚
Your path report came back clear.
你的胃里没有癌细胞
There are no cancerous cells in your stomach.
你的疼痛又是怎么回事
How's your pain?
伤还有点疼  不是很糟对吗
Uh the wound hurts a little. not too bad right?
是啊
Yeah.
你还记得
Don't you remember
妈妈临终前有多疼吗
How much pain mom was in at the end?
不记得了
No.
你那时帮我用冰块敷她的嘴唇
You used to help me wet her lips with an ice cube.
很糟糕  她甚至都不能喝东西
It was awful. she couldn't even drink.
她身上到处是管子
She had so many tubes everywhere.
我不记得了  我妈死的时候我才两岁
I don't remember. I was 2 years old when mom died.
唯一记得的理由是我难过又害怕
The only reason I know it was sad and horrible
因为你一直这样告诉我
Is because you tell me all the time.
对于葬礼我没有阴影
I don't have nightmares about funerals.
我没有吓坏然后认为是癌症
I don't freak out and think it's cancer
每次我消化不良
Every time I have indigestion.
你是  麦克
You do. Mike--
这是你的恐惧
This is your fear.
不是我的
It's not mine.
所以
So just...
等我也害怕的时候再让我再做这个决定吧
Let me decide when I'm scared.
把速度加到300
Let's take the pace up to 300.
重要器官还很稳定  这不是关键的
Vitals are still stable. this is pointless.
资料显示没有心率不齐的反应
The study is showing no sign of arrhythmia.
等等  心跳超速  她心跳超速了
Wait. v-tach. she's in v-tach.
很好只是对你很难
All right let's just very hard for you.
-调到3-3-0  -BP低于六十高于10
-Take it to 3-3-0.  -b.p.'s down 60 over 10.
-340  该死  -她没醒  快到这来柯瑞夫
- 340. damn it.- she's not breaking.Karev get in there now.
止住休克
Wait hold the shock.
她挺过来了
She's coming out.
可能是致心律失常性右室心肌病
This could be a.r.v.c.
右心房导致了心率不齐
The right ventricle's causing the arrhythmia.
她的大脑没有氧气供应
Her brain doesn't get oxygen--
-导致她癫痫发作 -我的天
-And then she seize -Oh my god
克莱夫你刚救了这姑娘的命
Karev you just saved this girl's life.
没关系  没关系
It's okay. it's okay.
呼吸
Just... just breathe.
按下去然后呼吸
Put the paddles down and breathe.
没关系
It's okay.
这不容易
Well it wasn't easy.
不只我完成
Not only did i push through
还有我的兔唇修复和中耳整复手术
My harelip reconstruction and a tympanoplasty
不过我漂亮的拔下了一个烧坏的移植片
But I pulled out a burn graft so beautiful
这简直催人泪下啊
It could bring a grown man to tears.
老大吗
Chief?
你有谢博德的消息不?
You haven't heard from shepherd have you?
没有  我没有
No sir. i haven't.
老大  我的确不想计较
Sir.Okay i have tried to let it go
因为我知道你对事不对人
Because I know it's not personal.
我理解  你现在很不好过
I understand it's very hard for you.
我明白你压力很大
I understand you're under a great deal of pressure.
不过你犯得着今天在手术室
But the way you yelled at me in the O.R. today
当着这么多人面吼我吗
In front of my residents?
这可不好  老大
Not okay sir.
完全不好
Not okay at all.
现在  你和我应该谈谈
Now... you and me we're just gonna have to find a way
如何好好共事
To work together.
所以你  就不和我说话了吗
So you... not talking to me now?
很好  真成熟啊  老大
Well that's... just real mature sir.
果真成熟
That's real mature.
我们得出诊断
We have a diagnosis.
请说  格雷医生
Go ahead dr. Grey.
唯一线索是X病人
Patient "x"--an elevated l.d.h.
有个升高的异柠檬酸脱氢酶
Was our only clue.
然后我们发现她有
Uh and then we found out that she had
扩大的肿瘤和可疑的痣
Enlarged lymph nodes and a suspicious mole
那个切片检查
Which was biopsied.
同时显影剂核磁共振显示转移
Meanwhile this m.r.i. with contrast showed a met
在她右裂片上
On her right temporal lobe
切片检查还显示细胞分裂
And the biopsy revealed dividing cells.
需要更进一步的测试
That coupled with further staging tests
得出我们最后对转移性恶性肿瘤的诊断
Led to our final diagnosis of metastatic melanoma
转移到肝脏和大脑
With mets to the liver skin and brain.
你的预测吗
Your prognosis?
做几个月的化疗
With chemo and radiation uh a few months.
最好这样  女孩的美丽很重要
At best. girl's pretty much toast.
存活率是百分之五
Survival rate's 5%.
如果我是她就好好给自己放个假
If i were her I'd go on a really good vacation.
或者去教堂祈求上帝宽恕  我不知道
Or go to church ask for forgiveness prayers.I don't know.
实习医生都立即做出反应
Interns all talking at once
做的很好
Good job everybody. whoo!
那是什么
That's it?
最后一次竞赛我们得了个奖
After the last contest we got a prize.
是什么奖
Yeah what's our prize?
你想  每次你诊断病人
You think every time you diagnosis a patient
定别人的死期就有奖了吗
Hand someone a death sentence there's a prize?
这个奖励就是
The prize is...
这次你们不能错
You didn't screw it up this time.
你们要实实在在的做对
The prize is you people actually did something right.
奖励是你们今天是医生了
The prize is you were doctors today.
你们是医生  那就是奖励
You were doctors. that is the prize.
阿戴尔吗  你在这干什么
Adele? what are you doing here?
会议室  理查  就现在
Conference room Richard. now.
你也是  米兰达  走吧
You too Miranda. let's go.
这是心率起搏器
It's a pacemaker.
用来调节你不正常的心率
It's going to regulate your abnormal arrhythmias
所以不会再有癫痫了
So you won't have any more seizures.
所以
So...
我不会再生病了
I'm not sick anymore.
一个摔跤手治好我了
A wrestler fixed me.
不全是  你的心脏还是有严重的问题
Not exactly. you still have a serious heart condition.
所以我们找来心脏病学专家来医治你
So we're gonna set you up with a cardiologist.
不过谁也没必要知道
but no one has to know
我的嘴巴不会起泡
I won't be frothing at the mouth.
我不用带手镯上课
I don't have to wear a bracelet to school.
我可以穿个衬衫遮住它
I can cover this with a shirt.
是啊  那有什么吗
Yeah. that's something huh?
是一切
It's everything.
一旦人们把你当病人你就什么都不是
Once people see you as sick they don't see anything else.
比姆先生打电话过来了  我们没有胜利
Mr. bimm just called. we did't get a trophy.
总还会有下一季对吧
There's always next season right?
是吧我们都这样想
Yeah we were thinking
也许你应该试试唱诗班和辩论赛
Maybe you should try out for choir or debate.
需要更少运动的爱好
Something requiring less movement.
我们只是担心你的安危
Yeah. we're just worried for your safety.
没必要那样  我们治好她了
You don't have to be. we fixed her.
癫痫骨病
Epileptic bone.
什么  还有这种病
What? there--there's no such thing as an epileptic bone.
你是医生吗
Are you a doctor?
那么她  现在完全正常了吗
So she's... like totally normal now?
你们没一个正常的  你们都是该死的蠢货
Dude none of you are normal. you're freaking band nerds.
因为你们吝啬荒谬还幼稚
Of all the petty ridiculous infantile--
你是在开医院还是游乐场啊
Are you running a hospital here or a playground?
阿戴尔我不会那样说的
Adele I will not be spoken to in that--
医院还是游乐场啊 理查得
Hospital or playground richard?!
医院
Hospital.
那么就开始像个医院领导的样子
Then start acting like the chief of a hospital
马上对那个女人道歉
And apologize to that woman right now.
对不起
Sorry.
这就叫道歉吗
You call that an apology?
现在你最好别离开这间屋子
Now you better not leave this room
直到你们两个把这解决
Until the two of you work this out
因为如果我再把自己拖到这来
Because if I have to drag myself down here
穿过拥堵的交通
Through rush-hour traffic again
去管这种屁事
to police this dir stomach out
阿戴尔你说自己的意见吧
Adele you've made your point.
你自己把这事擦屁股吧
and you wipe that smir stomach out
你也没好到哪里去  跟人家老婆说人闲话
You're no better-- tattling on a man to his wife.
当你的胃被切除后
When you have your stomach out
你就再也不能吃糖了
You can't eat sugar anymore.
如果他那么做了
If he's doing this
是因为他不想放弃他该死的咖喱豆
Because he doesn't want to give up his damn jelly beans...
我想不止这样  或许
I think it's more than that. or
足球还有姑娘什么的
football or girls
管他是什么
Whatever the hell it is.
跟别的选择比起来不算什么
It doesn't matter not compared to the alternative.
好吧我们会尽可能的警惕
Well we'll be as vigilant as we can.
我们用所有可用的过滤器
We'll use every screening tool available.
那没必要  迈克尔要做这手术
That won't be necessary. Mikey's gonna have the surgery.
也许不是今天  不过我会盯着他
Maybe not today but i'm gonna be on him like glue
在我弥留之际直到他也是
To my dying breath until he does.
如果他想逃避的话
and if he just wantnd hide from it
你不用让你爱的人独自呆着  格雷医生
You don't leave the people you love alone dr. Grey.
这个傻子可能还不知道
That idiot may not know it yet
我的恐惧可以救他的性命
But my fear is what's gonna save his life.
今天我学到很多
I learned a lot today--
治疗一个病人从开始到最后
Diagnosing a patient from beginning to end.
所以  谢谢你
So... thank you
教我们这些
For teaching us.
你想说什么
What would you say?
对X病人
To patient "x"--
你想要  想要宣布消息吗
How would you-- how would you break the news?
我想说很对不起
I would say that is very sorry
然后支持团队
And--and that there were support groups that...
我  我不知道
I don't--i don't know.
要是你的话怎么说
What--what do you say to somebody who's--who's gonna...
你说  他们有一个选择
You say... they have a choice.
他们可以逃避
They can run away and hide from it
或者面对
Or they can face it.
你说他们需要陪在他们爱的人身边
You say they need to be around the people who love them
因为那会是他们一生中最难的斗争
Because it's gonna be the toughest fight of their life
没有谁必须独自面对
And no one should have to do it alone.
你给了他们希望
And then you give them the odds.
甚至是百分之五的生存几率也很糟
And even though a 5% survival rate is bad
真的很糟
It's really bad
你说
You say...
去他妈的希望
Screw the odds.
人们死于打嗝
People die of the hiccups.
我妈就是死于打嗝
My mother died of the hiccups.
这个的生存几率是百分百吧
And survival rate for that is what 100%?
所谓几率就是她现在应该活着
The odds are that she should be alive right now.
机率  机率没有任何意义
The odds are that the--the odds mean crap.
这样病人就能面对现实  顽强抗争
So people should face it and they should fight.
也许不该这么说
Maybe not those words.
没错
No.
就该这样说
Exactly those words.
谢谢你  格蕾医生
Thank you dr. grey.
她怎么样了
How's she doing?
她  她很稳定
Uh she's uh she's stable.
你今天表现的不错
You did a hell of a job today
我会跟主任说的
And the chief is gonna hear about it.
对你印象深刻啊
pretty impressivetude of yours
端正了自己的态度
You fix that attitude of yours
你会在这里有所作为的
You could be the future of this hospital
拭目以待
The one to watch.
你行的  克莱夫
You go karev.
伊兹
Iz!
亨特让我做
Hunt's letting me do
末梢结合
The distal anastomosis on his fem-pop.
-太棒了  -真了不起
- That's awesome. - it's crazy.
他们还说  我会在这里有所作为
They just told me i could be the future of this hospital
我可能会成为住院医师
That i'm the resident to watch.
我是说  我不是那种...
And that's... i mean... i'm not the kinda guy who--
我仕途不顺   屡遭挫折
Like i don't rise okay? i sink to the bottom.
现在我得到了一切  得到了尊重还有你
And now i'm getting all this-- this respect and you...
你不要把时间再浪费在
You--you gotta stop wasting all your time
"X"病人这种无聊的事上
With this patient "x" crap.
-阿历克斯  -我知道你喜欢教学  那很棒
- Alex    - i know you like teaching and that's great
可是你需要从真正的手术中
But you need to start treating real patients
诊断真正的病人
With real surgeries
因为一旦病人看到你消沉  就没戏了
Because once they see you as weak it's over.
伊兹  你会是个很好的医生
And iz you could be a great surgeon.
我们会很幸福
We could be great together.
你只是  不能再在纠结了
You just--you gotta stop screwinground
因为如果没有你陪在我身边
Because i don't want to be the future of this hospital
我不想在这里有任何作为
If you're not there with me
明白吗
Okay.
明白了
OK
阿历克斯
Alex!
怎么了
What?
你跟阿戴尔告状
You told adele on me?
主任  你不跟我说话
You stopped speaking to me sir.
我别无选择
That didn't exactly leave me many options.
我想知道  如果我为了神经科或者心脏科而放弃外科
I'd like to know would you have reacted like this
你的反应也会是这样吗
If i had left general surgery for neuro or cardio?
什么意思
I don't follow.
还是因为你觉得儿科太软弱了
Or is it because you regard peds as a soft specialty?
-你就为这事不爽吗  -太可笑了
- Is that what's bothering you?  - oh that's ridiculous.
也许是吧  我觉得
Well maybe but it seems to me
每一次我做点什么事儿  你觉得我软弱
That every time i do something that you perceive as soft
比如说生孩子
Like having a baby
花时间看孩子
Taking some time off to see my baby
我专攻儿科  你就觉得我没前途
Specializing in babies i'm dead to you.
-你想知道我是怎么想得吗 主任 -别太详细
-You want to know what i think sir? -not particular.
我觉得是你自己变得软弱了  所以你害怕
I think you're scared that you've gone soft.
你把整个医院的衰退归罪与它
You blame this whole hospital's decline on it
你知道我对这事什么看法吗
And you want to know what i think about that?
反正你不会告诉我的
you don't tell me anyway
对你一点好处也没有
It's not doing you one bit of good.
说这里的外科也跟着在下滑
I mean surgeons are still dropping like dominoes Around here
也许是时候了
So maybe it's time
你该面对你软弱的一面
That you got in touch with your feminine side.
也许你需要一点软弱
Maybe you need a little soft.
你没必要让我这么没面子
You still shouldn't have ratted me out.
抱歉
Sorry.
我也很抱歉
Me too.
你  你干嘛
Wh-what are you doing?
安排我明天跟你去处理外伤  克里斯蒂娜  你
Assigning myself to trauma with you tomorrow. cristina you--
你知道我很坚强
You know i'm a big girl.
我可以处理好自己的外伤
I can handle my share of trauma.
我已经想清楚了  也决定了
And i get to decide when i've had enough.
会有许多比噩梦更可怕的东西会吓到我
It's gonna take a lot more than a bad dream to scare me off.
不只是一个噩梦
It's more than a bad dream.
我明白
I know.
我知道
i know...
我没资格要求你什么
I have no business asking you for anything.
可是我需要你的帮助
But i need your help.
帮我让德瑞克回来
I need you to bring derek back.
虽然他状况不是很好
And he's not fine.
有时候  人们只是想一个人静一静
Sometimes people just want to be left alone.
他打算求婚
He's planning to propose.
他整个星期都随身带着求婚戒指
He's been carrying around a big ring for weeks.
他并不想一个人呆着
That's not a man who wants to be left alone.
我只是觉得你应该知道
I just thought you should know.
我们机会渺茫
Yes the odds are against us
我是个扫帚星  只会给你带来伤害
I'm a one-woman wrecking ball. all i do is break you--
你的手  你的小弟弟  你的朋友  你的生活
Your hand your penis your relationships your life.
我们在一起的机率只有百分之三
I'd say our survival rate is about 3%
而且  这  这很不好
And that's--that's-- that's bad.
也不是说完全没希望  我认为
But it's not nothing and--and i don't think
没到最后我们不能就放弃  因为...
That we should give up on this at least not yet because--
好吧
Okay.
小格蕾  你觉得伤害了我吗
You think you broke me little grey?
是你拯救了我
You're the one who put me back gether.
我的手
Hand.
马克
Uh mark.
有几封谢博德的邮件需要查收一下
I've got a couple of shepherd's post-ops to check in on
可是你好像喝多了
But after that you feel like a drink?
改天怎么样  约翰
How 'bout a rain check john?
是吉姆
Jim.
我叫吉姆
It's jim.
我今天过得很不错
So... i've had quite a day.
阿历克斯·克莱夫步我的后尘
Got my ass handed to me by alex karev
第二年就能成为住院医师
A second-year resident
一个害羞的外科医生
Which is humbling for a surgeon
还自称无所不知
Especially a know-it-all type-a--
我们没必要这么做  没必要装作是朋友
We don't have to do this. we don't have to be friends.
这里很大的  有那么多楼层
It's a big hospital with lots of floors
很多地方可以躲  我挺好的
Lots of places to hide and i'm perfectly okay
接下来的几年我会这么做
With doing that for the next few years
你没在听我说吗
you're not hearing
我有时候会恐慌
Sometimes i panic in the moment
我叫它犯错  我判断错了形式
And i call it wrong. i misjudge a situation.
如果你准备好了
So if you're up for it
我想约你吃晚饭
I'd like to take you to dinner.
也许吧
Maybe.
也许
Maybe?
最近事儿比较多
Yeah my schedule's kind of insane right now.
有空了我会联系你的
So i'll uh get back to you.
明天怎么样
How's uh tomorrow?
晚安  伊兹
Good night iz.
晚安
Night.
我一直在刻意保持距离
Um... i've been keeping my distance
因为你跟阿历克斯在一起
'cause you're with alex
我只是想让你知道
But i just want to let you know
我还在你身边  关心着你
I'm still here i still care.
谢谢  乔治
Thanks george.
你不想跟我说说吗
And you don't want to talk about it?
现在不想
Not yet.
好吧  晚安
Okay. good night.
安
Night.
你不怎么喜欢我  是吧
You don't like me very much do you?
没关系的
Uh-- no it's good.
没关系  因为我想跟你说点事
It's good because i need to tell you something.
我告诉你是因为我想跟别人说说
I need to tell you because i need to tell somebody
而且  你很冷血
And... and you're a robot.
你承受的了
You can take it.
说吧
Okay.
我不能在这里说  不能
I can't tell you here. i-i can't.
好吧
Okay.
我不能
I can't.
好吧
Okay.
好的
你把所有的衣服  都从家里的衣柜拿走了
You cleaned all of your clothes Out of the closet at the house.
回去吧  小梅  回家吧
go home mer. just go home.
你打算在这里躲多久
Well how long are you planning on hiding out here?
你正在这么做  你在逃避
Because that's what you're doing. yore hiding.
你犯了错
You made a mistake.
她的死是你不能逃避的事实
She's dead and you can't hide from that.
我没有逃避  我完了
I'm not hiding. i'm done.
我不再做手术了
I'm done operating.
好吧  你放弃了
Oh okay. so you're just quitting?
你应该比任何人都跟清楚
You should understand better than anybody else.
你对这些很在行  放弃  逃跑  逃避
You wrote the book on quitting running hiding.
梅丽狄斯  你逃避过很多
You've written a lot of books meredith.
也许是这样  可是我现在在这里
That may be true but i'm here now.
你现在在这里
Mm. hmm. you're here now?
我刚搬进你家的时候  你就想把我撵出来
You've wanted me out since the day i moved in.
不是那样
That is not true.
因为你对承诺的事情无能为力
because you're incapable Of anything that resembles commitment.
你欺骗了我
You lied to me.
你说过你没事了  放下了过去
You said you were healthy that you... you were healed.
根本没有  你是在伪装
There's no fixing you. u're lemon.
德里克·谢博德你喝醉了
Derek shepherd you are drunk.
还在气头上
And you're angry.
我当时在场  所以我明白
And i've been there so i get it.
可是你没有权利
But that does not give you the
就这么走了
right-- just gong anywhere.
你不是打算就站在这  跟我说...
You don't get to just stand here and tell me--
你就想这样吗
this is what you want.?
-走吧  -我哪也不去
- Go. - i'm not going anywhere.
我说了  走开  梅丽狄斯  走开
I said leave! meredith leave!
我知道你打算求婚
I know there's a ring.
什么
What?
主任告诉我了  我知道你准备了戒指
The chief told me. i know there's a ring.
你想要戒指
You want the ring?
给你
Here's your ring.
每一个手术都会留下阴影
Every surgeon has a shadow...
你就这点本事吗
Is that the best you've got?
我不会走的  我们要一起承担
'cause i'm not bailing. we're in this together.
回家吧  梅丽狄斯
Go home meredith!
走出阴影的唯一方法
And the only way to get rid of a shadow...
就是把灯关掉
Is to turn off the lights...
不再逃避黑暗
To stop running from the darkness...
直面恐惧
And face what you fear...
绝不退缩
Head-on.